Katharine Oliver Gilly, RN, BSN

1456 Arabella Street New Orleans, Louisiana 70115 Cell: (504)952-0111 Home: (504) 729-0445 Kogilly@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Caring and dedicated Registered Nurse who has 4 years of experience in the Emergency and Recovery Room settings. Has the ability to provide the best care possible in a variety of different settings and communicate with all colleagues to ensure that the patient and their family receive the highest quality of care available.

Licenses

Board Certification for Emergency Nursing
TNCC - Trauma Nurse Core Course
ENPC- Emergency Nurse Pediatric Course
Basic Life Support (BLS) Certification 2012-2014
Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) Certification 2012-2014
Pediatric Life Support (PALS) Certification 2012-2014
Registered Nurse in Alabama, License number 1-125030, 12/31/2014
Registered Nurse in Louisiana, License number RN131730, 1/31/2015
Registered Nurse in Texas, License number 825368, 11/30/2014
CPR certified through American Heart Association

Skill Highlights

-Strong C	Clinical	Judgment	& Skills
-----------	----------	----------	----------

- -Organized
- -Patient and Family Advocacy
- -Flow Sheet Charting
- -Leader

- -Professional Bedside Manner
- -Enthusiastic Caregiver
- -Implements Treatment Protocols
- -Caring and Compassionate
- -Prioritizing/Managing Deadlines
- -Culturally Competent Care
- -Meditech, Cerner, & EPIC Trained

Professional Experience

Admit/PACU RN

August 2013 to Present

Vivere-Audubon Surgery Center- New Orleans, LA

RNs provide patient care in the Ambulatory Surgery Center setting focused on infertility, gynecology, and urology. Patients care is focused on orienting the patient and their spouse to the center, completing needed pre-operative assessments and paperwork and preparing the patient for the upcoming procedure. Also, the RN helps to arrange for semen collection from the spouse when doing an oocyte retrieval, correlating the schedule with the anesthesiologist for coverage, and to assure that all clinical policies and procedures related to the admission and recovery of the patient are being followed. Additionally, the center performed their first procedure in November 2013. The RN helped to prepare the center for opening and their Accreditation Associate for Ambulatory Health Care survey.

Admit/PACU RN

December 2012 to August 2013

West Bank Surgery Center- Harvey, LA

Patient care is focused on working with a team of nurses to admit patients to West Bank Surgery Center, a multi-specialty surgery center, along with orienting patients to the facility, completing needed pre-operative assessments and paperwork and helping to prepare the patient for the upcoming procedure. Patient care was focused on monitoring the patient closely during the recovery period until appropriate for

discharge based on the facility's policy. Additionally, the Admit/PACU RN is to complete pre-operative assessments prior to the day of surgery along with post operative follow up care.

Emergency Room RN

May 2011 to December 2012

Interim LSU Public Hospital - New Orleans, LA

Provided care in the Emergency Room of a Level One Trauma Center with 29 beds, 2 trauma bays and over 40,000 patient visits annually. Care was focused on assessment of patients, prioritizing care, and management of multiple critically ill patients simultaneously, monitoring patients during moderate sedation along with providing care and compassion to patients and their family members. The role of the RN in the ER was also expanded to caring for the mentally ill of the community, triage patients based on acuity, and remaining up to date with nursing competencies and certifications.

Emergency Room RN

January 2011 to May 2011

East Jefferson General Hospital - Metairie, LA

The role of the RN, along with fellow team members, was to ensure the overall well-being of all patients during their stay in the Emergency Room. Critical thinking and prioritization were required along with admitting and discharging patients from the Emergency Room, participating in patient resuscitation, and caring for the mentally ill patients of the community.

Emergency Room RN

January 2010 to December 2010

DCH Regional Medical Center – Tuscaloosa, AL

Initial professional nursing career involved being oriented to the field of Emergency Nursing, development of basic nursing skills with a focus in the management of the critically ill and injured patients and further advancing assessment skills of patients, how to prioritize care, and how to effectively communicate with fellow staff.

Child Care Provider

December 2002 to December 2010

Lane Family - New Orleans, LA

Helped the family with caring for their autistic son.

Education and Training

Capstone College of Nursing, The University of Alabama December 2009

Tuscaloosa, AL, USA Nursing Bachelor of Science in Nursing

Additional Information

Member of the Emergency Nurses Association